人人影视
YYeTs.com
原创翻译 双语字幕
■
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.YYeTs.com
双语制作: 七色九天  飞雪
■
洛杉矶 公元2029年
那些机器从核子战火中崛起
它们灭绝人类的战争肆虐数十年
但最后的一场仗不会在未来掀起
它会发生在这里  就是现在
就在今晚
片名: 终结者
洛杉矶1984年凌晨1点52分
怎么了?  他妈的
What the hell? Goddamn son-of-a-bitch
什么事?
What the hell?
轮到我了
Hey, my turn.
来吧
come on
这个人在搞什么鬼?
Hey, what's wrong with this picture?
夜色很好  适宜散步?
Nice night for a walk?
夜色很好  适宜散步
Nice night for a walk.
明天是洗衣日  没干净衣服穿  是吗?
Wash day tomorrow. Nothing clean, right?
对  没干净衣服
Nothing clean. Right.
这个家伙一定是喝醉了
I think this guy's a couple of cans short of a six-pack.
你的衣服  马上给我
Your clothes, give them to me.
-快啊  -去你的  混蛋
-Now.  -Fuck you, asshole.
嘿  甜心  怎么样?
Hey, sugar, how about it?
我不必忍受那个的
I don't have to put up with that bullshit, man.
她老是缠着我
She's always after me.
兄弟  你有没有见到一道强光?
Hey, buddy, did you just see a real bright light?
-看到那家伙吗?  -别动
-See that guy?  -Hold it right there.
-他在逃跑  -别动  去吧
-He's rabbiting.  -Hey! I said hold it! Go.
那个混蛋抢了我的裤子
That son-of-a-bitch took my pants.
-今天是什么日子?  日期  -5月12号
-What day is it? The date.  -12th May.
-星期四  -什么年份?
-Thursday.  -What year?
他抢了我的枪  快追
He's got my gun. Let's go.
萨拉·康纳
大块头  替我守着它
Guard it for me, Big Buns.
你好  我迟到了
Hi. I'm late.
我也是
So am I.
萨拉·康纳
-开工了  -我也是
-I'm in it.  -So am I.
-麻烦你拿咖啡给我  好吗?  -好的
-Honey, can I have that coffee now?  -Yes, sir.
-牛排是谁的?  -我叫了烤牛肉
-OK. Who gets the burly-beef?  -I ordered barbecued.
我叫的  但我没有叫薯条
That's mine, but I didn't order fries.
-我叫的是辣牛肉  -谁点牛排?
-Mine's the chilli beef deluxe. -Who gets the burly-beef?
-我们想点菜  -好的
-We're ready to order now.  -Yes, ma'am.
对不起
I'm so sorry.
这不是真皮吧?
This isn't real leather, is it?
孩子  做得好  我该把小费给你
Nice going, kid. I ought to give you the tip.
要这样想  一百年后谁会在乎?
Look at it this way. In 100 years, who's gonna care?
那支12口径自动步枪
The 12-gauge auto-loader.
意大利制造  可以选手动或自动
That's ltalian. You can go pump or auto.
点45口径滑动式配镭射瞄准器
The 45 long slide with laser sighting.
全新的  我们刚收到的  是支好枪
These are new. We just got them in. That's a good gun.
镭射光亮起时
The beam comes on,
你把红点对准目标就行
you put the red dot where you want the bullet to go.
百发百中
You can't miss.
-还有什么需要?  -40瓦的同步等离子步枪
-Anything else? -Plasma rifle in the 40-watt range.
就是你看到的了
Hey, just what you see, pal.
那支乌兹型九毫米
The Uzi nine millimetre.
你很熟识枪械
You know your weapons, buddy.
任何一支都适合家居防卫
Any one of these is ideal for home defence.
那么  要哪一支呢?
So which will it be?
-全部  -今天可以提早关门了
-All.  -I may close early today.
手枪要等15日  但步枪现在就能拿走了
It's a 15-day wait on the handguns, but the rifles you can take now.
-你不能这样做  -错
-You can't do that.  -Wrong.
你好  宝贝  是我
Hi, baby. Yeah, yeah, it's me.
我要你来接我  我的电单车坏了
Listen, I need you to come pick me up. My bike just broke down.
我不管你在做什么  快来接我  什么...
I don't care what you're doing. Come and get me. What the...?
莫特?
Matt!
你的态度很有问题
Hey, man, you got a serious attitude problem.
莫特  你在哪里?
Matt! where are you
别这样  你在干什么?
come on  what are you doing?
萨拉·康纳...
-萨拉·康纳?  -是的
-Sarah Connor?  -Yes?
我在休息  卡拉代替我
I'm on my break, Chuck. Carla's got my station.
萨拉  过来  这算是跟你有关的
Sarah, come here. It's about you. I mean, sort of.
-不可思议  你不会相信的  -你会喜欢这个的
-Incredible.You're not gonna believe this.  -You're going to love this.
-什么?  -有几个目击证人指出
-What?  -compiled from several witnesses.
又一位萨拉·康纳  35岁  有两名子女
Once again, Sarah Connor, 35, mother of two,
今天下午在家里中枪身亡
brutally shot to death this afternoon.
你死了
You're dead, honey.
如果你喜欢音响
if you're into sound,
最佳的音响 就是鲍博立体声
for the greatest sound around, come to Bob's Stereo at 2500 Sepulveda.
我们有低音炮 高频炮 数码扬声器和镭射唱片
We've got woofers, tweeters, the newest in audio and compact discs.
还有图表均衡器和音响平衡器
We've got graphic equalisers and sound balancers that
对不起
Sorry.
你好
Hello?
首先  我会一个个的解开你的衫钮
First I'm gonna rip the buttons off your blouse one by one,
然后用舌头 从你的头舔到你赤裸的乳房
then run my tongue down your neck to your bare, gleaming breasts.
然后慢慢地  逐英寸地脱掉你的牛仔裤
And then slowly...slowly pull your jeans off inch by inch.
金珍  是马特
Ginger, it's Matt.
然后舔你的肚皮...再往下面去
And lick your belly in circles further and further down,
然后用牙齿...脱掉你的内裤
and then pull your panties off with my teeth.
你是谁?
Who is this?
天啊  萨拉?
God. Sarah?
我的天  对不起
Jesus. I'm sorry.
我以为你是...我想找金珍
I thought you were...Can I talk to Ginger?
好的
Sure.
是那个变态鬼
It's the creep.
你好
Hello?
首先  我会一个个解开你的衫钮
First I'll rip the buttons off your blouse one by one...
你们这群混蛋  等着我对付你们  放手
You fucking pigs. Wait till I get my hands on you. Get off me.
坐下
sit down
艾特
Ed.
-你有什么?  -女死者
-What have you got?  -Dead girl.
-我看得到  -萨拉·康纳  秘书  35岁
-I can see that.  -Sarah Ann Connor, secretary, 35.
在不足十英尺内身中六枪  大口径武器
Shot six times at less than 10 feet. Large calibre weapon.
我看得清楚
You know, these work.
-这是什么?  -第二名女死者
-What's this?  -Dead girl two.
今天下午山谷区分区送过来的
Sent over from the Valley division this afternoon.
我肯定这些命案是有动机的
Are you sure there's a point to all of this?
看看死者的名字
Look at the name, Ed.
萨拉·路易斯·康纳...有没有弄错?
Sarah Louise Connor. Is this right?
你说笑吧
You're kidding.
报纸会大做文章的
The press is gonna be short-stroking it.
-一个有特定模式的凶手  -我讨厌古怪的案件
-A one-day pattern killer.  -I hate the weird ones.
所以...
So...
比凡人得到的更好
Better than mortal man deserves.
-你有见过宝斯利吗?  -最近没有
-Ginger, have you seen Pugsley?  -Not lately.
-你听了口信没有?  -我以为你听了
-Did you check messages?  -I thought you did.
-萨拉  是妈  -原来你在这里
-Hi, Sarah, this is your mom...  -There you are, young man.
你想想你妈吧
You mind your mother.
再见
Bye
你好  萨拉  莫仕庭  有突发事件
Hi, Sarah. Stan Morsky. Something's come up.
我不能应约了  我不能丢下不理的
Looks like I won't be able to make it tonight. Just can't get out of it.
对不起  我会给你赔罪的
I'm really sorry. I'll make it up to you.
改天找你吧  对不起  再见
Call you in a day or so. Bye.
那个混蛋  有辆保时捷又怎样
That bum. So what if he has a Porsche?
他不能这样对你的  这可是周五晚上
He can't treat you like this. It's Friday night, for Christ's sake.
我没事的
I'll live.
我会打爆他的膝盖
I'll break his kneecaps.
宝斯利仍然爱我  是吗?
Well, Pugsley still loves me. Don't you, baby?
天  真恶心
God. It's disgusting.
我去看电影  你和马特玩得开心点
I'm gonna go to a movie, kiddo. You and Matt have a good time.
-我们会的  你也是  -好的
-We will. You, too.  -OK.
该死  马特
Damn it, Matt.
该死
Shit.
这些命案 是依电话簿里的次序发生的?
These killings occurred in the order of their listings in the phone book.
-我可以说什么?  无可奉告  -但是...
-What can I tell you? No comment. -But, Lieutenant...
那杯咖啡早就凉了
That coffee's two hours cold.
我还用它弄熄香烟
I put a cigarette out in it.
-找到下一名女子了吗?  -没  只有电话留言
-Did you reach the next girl yet? -No. I got her answering machine.
-派组人去  -已经派了  还没回音
-Send a unit.  -I sent a unit. There's no answer.
-那个经理还没回家  -打电话给她
-The apartment manager's not in.  -Call her.
-刚打了  -再打
-I just called her.  -Call her again.
给我一支香烟
Give me a cigarette.
你好  捉弄到你了  你在跟留言机谈话
Hi, there. Fooled you. You're talking to a machine.
但别害羞  留言机也需要爱的  跟它谈谈吧
But don't be shy. It's OK. Machines need love, too, so talk to it...
金珍  是我啦...
and Ginger, that's me,
或者萨拉会回复你的  等候哔哔声啦
or Sarah will get back to you. Wait for the beep.
又是一样
Same shit.
我现在听到了 就叫他"电话簿杀手"吧
I can hear it now. He's gonna be called the goddamn Phone Book Killer.
我讨厌这些触目案件  特别是变态的案件
I hate these press cases. Especially the weird press cases.
-你去哪里?  -发表声明
-Where are you going?  -To make a statement.
叫这班走狗替我们工作
Maybe make these jackals work for us.
若我11点前能上电视  或许她会找我们的
If I can get on the tube by eleven o'clock, maybe she'll call us.
怎样?  我的样子怎样?
Well, how do I look?
-很难看  老总  -不错
-Like shit, boss.  -Your mama.
刚收到消息  警方已经宣布了
This just in. Police have announced the name of the victim
今天发生的命案的  第二名死者的姓名
in the second of two murders which took place today.
奇怪的是  两名死者都是同名同姓
Incredibly, the names of the two victims are virtually identical.
两小时前  35岁的萨拉·康纳...被发现死在寓所里
Two hours ago, 35-year-old Sarah Ann Connor was pronounced dead...
-转台吧  -萨拉·路易斯...
-Can we change this?  -Sarah Louise...
别碰它
Don't touch it.
在她家中被杀
murdered earlier today in her home.
警方拒绝猜测
Police are refusing to speculate
两宗案件的类同之处
on the similarity between the shooting deaths
现在仍未发现两者之间有何关连
and no other connection between the two victims has been established yet.
我们会随时为大家报导最新消息
We'll have more on this late-breaking story as it comes in.
萨拉·康纳...
黑科技酒吧
-有电话吗?  -在里面
-Hey, you got a phone?  -It's in the back.
四元五角
Hey. Four-fifty.
你已接通洛杉矶警局紧急热线
You have reached the Los Angeles Police emergency number.
所有线路正忙
All lines are busy.
如需警车支援  请稍候
If you need a police car sent out to you, stay on the line.
走开  我会拿你来制皮带
Go on. I'm gonna make a belt out of you.
别逼我打你
Don't make me bust you up, man.
你好  捉弄到你了  你在跟留言机谈话
Hi, there. Fooled you. You're talking to a machine.
但别害羞  留言机也需要爱的
But don't be shy. It's OK. Machines need love, too.
跟它谈谈吧...金珍 是我啦 或者萨拉会回复你的
So talk to it and Ginger, that's me, or Sarah will get back to you.
等候哔哔声啦
Wait for the beep.
金珍  我是萨拉  快接听
Ginger. This is Sarah. Pick up if you're there.
我在比高大道的黑科技酒吧  我很害怕
I'm at this place on Pico Boulevard called Tech Noir. I'm really scared.
有人跟踪我
I think that there's somebody after me.
我希望你快点听这个口信
I hope that you play this back soon.
我想让你和马特尽快来接我
I need you and Matt to come and pick me up as soon as possible.
警方不停转驳我的电话线  我会再试的
The police keep transferring me. I'm gonna give 'em another try.
这里的号码是5559175  快回电  我要你帮忙
The number here is 5559175. Call me, kiddo. I need your help.
萨拉·康纳
是她
It's her.
-萨拉·康纳? 我是戴探长  -听着...
-Sarah Connor? It's Lieutenant Traxler.  -Listen...
别要我等或者转线
Don't put me on hold. Don't transfer me to another department.
-我不会  -你在哪?
-I won't.  -Can you tell me where you are?
-一间叫黑科技的酒吧  -我知道 在比高大道
-I'm in this bar called Tech Noir. -I know it. It's on Pico.
-你没事吧?  -没事  但我不想离开
-Are you all right? -Yeah, but I don't wanna leave.
-我觉得有人在跟踪我  -留心听着
-I think there's a guy following me.  -Now, listen carefully.
你身处公众地方  会较安全的
You're in a public place so you'll be safe.
留在显眼处  别出去  别上厕所
Stay visible. Don't go outside.
-我会很快派车来  -好的
-I'll have a car there in a minute.  -OK.
那个家伙没有付钱
Hey, that guy didn't pay.
你想活着就跟我来
Come with me if you wanna live.
快点
Come on!
这是1-L19  有人袭击后逃跑
This is one-L-19. I got a hit-and-run felony.
可疑车辆是旧型灰色福特 在第七街向西逃走
Suspect vehicle -Iate model grey Ford headed westbound on Seven.
他开得很快
He's really moving -punching lights.
马上派救护车 来第七街和百老汇街交界
I'm gonna need an ambulance at Seventh and Broadway right now.
别动
Hold it.
Hold on.
你有没有受伤?  你有没有中枪?
Are you injured? Are you shot?
照我的说话做  照着做
Do exactly what I say. Exactly.
没我允许不准动  不准发出声音
Don't move unless I say. Don't make a sound unless I say.
明白吗?
Do you understand?
-明白吗?  -明白  求你别伤害我
-Do you understand?  -Yes. Please don't hurt me.
我是来帮你的
I'm here to help you.
我姓李斯 科技步队中士DN38416 受命来保护你
I'm Reese. Sergeant Tech-Com. DN38416. Assigned to protect you.
你是被毁灭的目标
You've been targeted for termination.
嫌犯在国民街与奥运道交界 1-L19 请通话
Attempt to intercept, 1-L19.
这是1-L19  在奥运道向西行 接近奥佛兰道
This is one-L19. Westbound on Olympic. Approaching Overland.
一定是搞错了  我没做过什么
This is a mistake. I didn't do anything.
不  你会做的  你活着很重要
No, but you will. It's very important that you live.
不可能  那个人怎能站起来追你...
This isn't true. How could that man just get up after you...
它不是人  是机器
It's not a man. A machine.
一个魔鬼终结者  电脑达因系统101型号
A Terminator. Cyberdyne Systems model 101 .
机器?  像机械人?
A machine? Like a robot?
不是机械人  是电子人  电脑控制的生物
Not a robot. A cyborg-cybernetic organism.
-不  他刚才在流血  -等一下
-No. He was bleeding.  -Just a second.
伏下
Get your head down.
魔鬼终结者是个混合体
Listen. The Terminator's an infiltration unit. .
半人半机械
Part man, part machine
内里是一个超合金的战斗骨架
Underneath it's a hyper-alloy combat chassis.
由微型处理器操作
Microprocessor controlled.
全副武装  非常强劲  但外表是活人组织
Fully armoured, very tough. Outside it's living human tissue.
肌肉 皮肤 毛发 血液 都是为电子人培植的
Flesh, skin, hair, blood  grown for the cyborgs.
-你想我怎样做?  -留心听着
-Look, Reese, I don't know  -Pay attention.
我要弃掉这辆车
I gotta ditch this car.
600系列有塑胶皮肤  很容易认得出
The 600-Series had rubber skin. We spotted them easy.
但这批是新造的  它们很像人类
But these are new. They look human.
流汗  口臭  诸如此类 很难辨认
Sweat, bad breath, everything. Very hard to spot.
我要等他向你下手  才能对付他
I had to wait till he moved on you before I could zero him.
听着 我不是蠢才 他们还不能制造那样的东西
Look, I am not stupid. They cannot make things like that yet.
还不可以  40年后就可以了
Not yet. Not for about forty years.
你是说它来自未来?
Are you saying it's from the future?
一个有可能的未来  从你的角度看
One possible future...from your point of view.
我对科技一窍不通
I don't know tech stuff.
那么你也是来自未来?
Then you're from the future, too. Is that right?
-对  -对
-Right. -Right.
电子人感觉不到痛楚  可我能  别再那样做
Cyborgs don't feel pain. I do. Don't do that again.
-放我走  -听着...还有搞清楚点
-Just let me go.  -Listen and understand.
那个毁灭者就在外面
That Terminator is out there.
它不讲情面  也不讲道理
It can't be bargained with, it can't be reasoned with.
它不会同情或后悔...或者恐惧
It doesn't feel pity or remorse or fear
它绝不会罢休  永远不会  直到你死掉
and it absolutely will not stop, ever, until you are dead.
你可否制止它?
Can you stop it?
我不知道
I don't know.
靠这些武器  我不知道
With these weapons, I don't know.
所有单位
All units.
在一个停车场里发现可疑车辆
Ford suspect vehicle has been found in a parking structure
地点是第四街和百老汇街交界
at Fourth and Beaudry.
李斯?  为何是我?
Reese, why me?
它为何要对付我?
Why does it want me?
曾经发生了一场核战
There was a nuclear war.
未来数年后
A few years from now,
这里的一切...这个地方  所有的东西
all this, this whole place, everything,
都会消失  就此消失
it's gone, just gone.
有一些生还者
There were survivors.
零星...散落各地
Here, there.
没有人知道是谁发动战争
Nobody even knew who started it.
-是那些机器  -我不明白
-It was the machines, Sarah.  -I don't understand.
防卫网络电脑
Defence network computers.
新型的  功能强劲
New, powerful,
接驳到所有东西  被委托操控一切重任
hooked into everything, trusted to run it all.
他们说它变得聪明起来  一种智能的新秩序
They say it got smart, a new order of intelligence.
它视所有人类为威胁
Then it saw all people as a threat.
不能与我们共存
Not just the ones on the other side.
它在刹那间决定了我们的命运
It decided our fate in a microsecond.
灭绝
Extermination.
你可有目睹这场战争?
Did you see this war?
没有  我在战后长大  在废墟中成长
No. I grew up after. In the ruins.
挨饥抵饿  躲避那些HK
Starving. Hiding from the H-Ks.
-HK?  -追捕杀手
-H-Ks?  -Hunter killers.
机械工厂制造的巡逻机器
Patrol machines built in automated factories.
我们大部分人被围捕  关在营里等候被消灭
Most of us were rounded up. Put in camps for orderly disposal.
这是被镭射素描器烙下的
This was burned in by laser scanner.
我们有部分人得以活下来  去干活
Some of us were kept alive. To work.
搬运尸体
Loading bodies.
那些消灭单位日以继夜的运作
The disposal units ran night and day.
我们差点就丧命
We were that close to going out for ever.
但有一个人...教我们反抗
But there was one man who taught us to fight.
冲击监禁营的线路
To storm the wire of the camps.
把那些金属混蛋撞个稀巴烂
To smash those metal mother fuckers into junk.
他扭转了局势  带我们脱离险境
He turned it around. He brought us back from the brink.
他姓康纳  约翰·康纳
His name was Connor. John Connor.
你的儿子  你未出世的儿子
Your son, Sarah. Your unborn son.
你来开车
Drive.
李斯
Reese!
不  李斯  不不  他们会杀死你的
No, Reese. No, no, no. They'll kill you.
在凯迪拉克里的人  立刻举高双手
You in the Cadillac, let me see your hands now.
下车
Get out of the car.
跪下
Drop to your knees.
-下车  -跪下
-Out of the car.  -Drop to the ground.
萨拉...喝一点吧
Sarah. Sarah, try to drink some of this.
你肯定是他们?
Listen, are you sure it's them?
我应该看看尸体的
I mean, maybe I should look at the bodies.
已经证实了他们的身份  没错的
No. They've been identified and there's no doubt.
金珍  小伙子
Ginger. Kiddo.
-萨拉  这是索博曼医生  -你好  萨拉
-Sarah, this is Dr Silberman.  -Hi, Sarah.
告诉他李斯对你说的一切  你应付得来吗
Tell him everything Reese told you, Sarah. Do you feel up to that?
可以吧
Yeah, I guess so.
-你是个医生?  -犯罪学心理医生
-You're a doctor?  -Criminal psychologist.
-李斯是不是疯的?  -这就是我们要查证的
-Is Reese crazy?  -That's what we're gonna find out.
你是个军人吧  保卫着谁?
So you're a soldier. Fighting for whom?
隶属贝里率领的第132团  从21年到27年
With the 132nd under Perry. From '21 to '27.
那是...2027年?
That's the year 2027?
对  后来我被派到...
That's right. Then I was assigned...
-很好  -当约翰·康纳的部下
-This is fucking great.  -under John Connor.
-敌人是谁?  -一个电脑防卫系统...
-Who was the enemy?  -A computer defence system...
该死  对不起
Goddamn! Sorry.
电脑动力系统替萨诺力制造的
built for SAC-NORAD by Cyberdyne Systems.
是吧
I see.
这个电脑认为
And this computer thinks .
杀了敌人的母亲  就能胜利
it can win by killing the mother of its enemy
把他在孕育前就杀掉
Killing him, in effect, before he's even conceived.
算是倒逆的堕胎?
A sort of retroactive abortion?
索博曼笑死我了  那家伙把他弄得一头雾水
Silberman cracks me up. Last week, a guy burned his Afghan.
-他先弄得一团糟  -闭嘴
-He screwed it first...  -Ed, shut up.
那么为何它...不杀死康纳约翰?
Why didn't the computer just kill Connor then?
为何要有这个毁灭者的计划?
Why this elaborate scheme with the Terminator?
它没有选择  它们的防御网络被催毁
It had no choice. Their defence grid was smashed.
我们赢了  杀掉康纳约翰也不会有何分别
We'd won. Taking out Connor then would make no difference.
天网要铲除他整个组织
Skynet had to wipe out his entire existence.
是不是当你们操控实验室 找到...
Is that when you captured the lab complex and found...
那个什么?
What is it called?
时空转移装置?
The time displacement equipment?
不错  那个毁灭者已经穿越过来了
That's right. The Terminator had already gone through.
康纳派我来拦截  它们炸毁了整个地方
Connor sent me to intercept and they blew the whole place.
那你怎么回去?
Well, how are you supposed to get back?
我回不去了
I can't.
没人能回家  也没人能过来
Nobody goes home. Nobody else comes through.
只有他...和我
It's just him and me.
为何你没带武器?  一些更先进的武器?
Why didn't you bring any weapons? Something more advanced.
你们没有镭射枪的吗?
Don't you have ray guns?
-镭射枪  -给我看看一件未来的科技
-Ray guns.  -Show me a piece of future technology.
你要光着身体
You go naked.
它跟由生物产生的磁场有关
Something about the field generated by a living organism
死物是不行的  那鬼东西不是我制造的
Nothing dead will go. I didn't build the fucking thing.
好的...但这个电子人  若它是金属的...
OK, OK. But this cyborg, if it's metal...?
-被活组织包着的  -对  是的
-Surrounded by living tissue.  -Oh, right.
好东西  我能因他功成名就
This is great stuff. I could make a career out of this guy.
看这个多聪明?  不需要证据
You see how clever this part is? It doesn't require a shred of proof.
大部分妄想狂都很复杂  但这个却很精明
Most paranoid delusions are intricate, but this is brilliant.
-为何另外两女会被杀  -大部分记录都在战争中遗失
-Why were the other women killed?  -Records were lost in the war.
天网对康纳的母亲几乎一无所知
Skynet knew almost nothing about Connor's mother.
不知道她的全名和地址  只知道在哪个城市
Her full name, where she lived. They just knew the city.
那个毁灭者只是受系统操控
The Terminator was just being systematic.
-我们再谈谈...  -你听得够多了
-Let's go back...  -Look, you have heard enough.
我已经回答了你的问题  现在我要见萨拉
I have answered your questions. I have to see Sarah Connor.
-我作不了主  -那为何我要跟你谈?
-I'm afraid that's not up to me.  -Then why am I talking to you?
-谁是主管?  -求你...
-Who is in authority here?  -Please...
闭嘴
Shut up!
你还是不明白  对不对?
You still don't get it, do you?
他会找到她  这就是他要做的  他只会这样做
He'll find her. That's what he does. That's all he does.
你阻止不了他
You can't stop him.
他会掐住她喉咙 挖出她心脏
He'll reach down her throat and pull her fucking heart out!
-医生  -放开我
-Doc.  -Let go of me!
对不起
Sorry.
他是疯子?
He's crazy?
用技术性的用语...他是个傻子
In technical terminology, he's a loon.
这是他们所谓的盔甲  我们的特种步队都穿着这个
Sarah, this is what they call body armour. Our TAC guys wear these.
挡到12口径的火力
It'll stop a 12-gauge round.
那个人一定是穿了它  触摸一下吧
This other man must've been wearing one under his coat. Feel that.
-打碎挡风玻璃又怎么说?  -他可能服了麻醉药
-What about he punched through the windshield. -He was probably on PCP.
就算断了骨头  他也感觉不到
Broke every bone in his hand. He wouldn't feel it.
-这个家伙...看见疤痕吗?  -拿着
-There was this guy once...You see this scar?  -Here.
谢谢
Thank you.
这里有一张沙发  躺下睡会吧
There's a couch in this other room. Stretch out and get some sleep.
你妈至少要一小时后  才能到这
Be at least an hour before your mother gets here.
-我睡不着  -试试吧
-I can't sleep.  -Try.
那张沙发其貌不扬  但很舒服的
It may not look it, but that couch is very comfortable.
你会绝对安全的  这座大厦里有30个警员
You'll be perfectly safe. We got 30 cops in this building.
谢谢你
Thank you.
-晚安  -晚安
-Good night.  -Good night.
我是萨拉·康纳的朋友
I'm a friend of Sarah Connor.
听说她在这  我能见她吗
I was told she's here. Could I see her?
不能  你不能见她 她在录口供
No. Can't see her. She's making a statement.
她在哪里?
Where is she?
要一会的
It make take a while.
你想等的话  那边有张长椅
If you wanna wait, there's a bench over there.
我会回来
I'll be back.
怎么回事?
What the hell was that?
有枪声
Gunshot!
-是不是恐怖分子?  -快走
-What is it, terrorists?  -Let's go
别走开
Stay here.
-我们快离开这里 -来吧
-Let's get out of here! -Come on!
快点...
Move it, move it!
我看到他
I got him
看着他
Watch him.
-自动式武器 -快点  走吧
- Automatic weapons!  -Lock and load! Let's go!
着火了...
Fire! Fire!
艾特
Ed
萨拉
Sarah!
李斯
Reese.
这边
This way.
现在是KFLB新闻时间 频道4.36
KFLB news time. 4.36.
主要新闻 加州历来最大型的
Top story, the largest single law enforcement mobilisation
执法行动正在展开
in California history is currently underway.
五个南部县区正在大举搜捕...
Police in five counties are engaged in a massive manhunt for...
拿着
Take this.
我们把这个推离公路
All right. Let's get this off the road.
-你冷吗?  -冻僵了
-You cold?  -Freezing.
李斯?
Reese?
-你有名字吗?  -凯尔
-You got a first name?  -Kyle.
凯尔  你穿越时空时是怎样的?
Kyle, what's it like when you go through time?
白光
White light.
痛楚
Pain.
-或许就像出生时一样吧  -我的天
-It's like being born maybe.  -My God.
我刚才吃了一记
I caught one back there.
-你中枪了?  -不是很严重
-You mean you got shot?  -It's not bad.
-我们要找医生  -没事的  算了吧
-We gotta get you to a doctor.  -It's OK. Forget it.
算了?  你疯的吗?  脱下它
What do you mean, forget it? Are you crazy? Take this off.
天
Jesus.
它穿过了皮肉
See? It passed right through the meat.
这会使我作呕
This is gonna make me puke.
-你跟我谈话好吗?  -谈什么?
-Would you just talk about something?  -What?
不知道  随便说吧  谈谈我的儿子
I don't know. Anything. Just talk. Tell me about my son.
他有我这么高大
He's about my height.
他有你的眼睛
He has your eyes.
他是怎样的?
What's he like?
你信任他  他有一种力量
You trust him. He's got a strength.
我愿意为约翰·康纳牺牲
I'd die for John Connor.
我现在至少知道给他取什么名字
Well, at least now I know what to name him.
你不知道他父亲是谁吧
Don't suppose you know who the father is
好让我遇上他时不会叫他滚开
so I won't tell him to get lost?
约翰从来没有提起他
John never said much about him.
-我知道他在战前死了  -等一会
-I know he dies before the war...  -Wait.
我不想知道
I don't wanna know.
是不是约翰派你来的?
So was it John that sent you here?
是我自愿的
I volunteered.
-为什么?  -有机会认识传奇人物
-Why?  -It was a chance to meet the legend.
萨拉·康纳  教她儿子去抵抗...组织
Sarah Connor, who taught her son to fight, organise,
准备  从他小时就这样教导他
prepare from when he was a kid.
当其他人还在战前躲避时
When you were in hiding before the war.
你用过去式说一些 我还没做的事
You're talking about things I haven't done yet in the past tense.
真的令我发疯
It's driving me crazy.
你肯定没找错人?
Are you sure you have the right person?
肯定
I'm sure.
不是吧  我像未来的母亲?
Come on! Do I look like the mother of the future?
我坚强又有组织能力吗?  我连平衡收支都不会
I mean, am I tough? Organised? I can't even balance my checkbook.
我没有要求这个荣誉  也不想要它
Look, Reese, I didn't ask for this honour and I don't want it.
绝对不要
Any of it.
你儿子有个口信给你  他要我背熟它
Your son gave me a message to give to you. Made me memorise it.
"感谢你在黑暗年代的勇气"
Thank you, Sarah, for your courage through the dark years.
"你要面对的事我帮不到你  未来还未定案"
I can't help you with what you must soon face. The future is not set.
"你一定要比你想像中更坚强"
You must be stronger than you imagine you can be.
"你一定要活下去  否则我永不会存在"
You must survive or I will never exist.
就是这样
That's all.
包扎得很好
It's a good field dressing.
你喜欢吗?
You like it?
这是我的第一次
It's my first.
睡一会吧  快天亮了
Get some sleep. It'll be light soon.
好的
OK.
再跟我谈一会
Talk to me some more.
谈什么?
About what?
告诉我你从哪里来
Tell me about where you're from.
好的
All right.
你白天躲起来  但晚上你可以到处活动
You stay down by day, but at night you can move around.
你仍然要小心  因为HK会用红外线
You still have to be careful because the H-Ks use infrared.
但它们还不够聪明  约翰教了对付它们的方法
But they're not too bright. John taught us ways to dust them.
就是当那些渗透者出现的时候
That's when the infiltrators started to appear.
毁灭者是最新型的...最难对付的
The Terminators were the newest. The worst.
它正在以搜寻模式闯进你的防区
Traversing your sector in search mode.
在你以北750米的位置
750 metres north ofyour position.
我们走吧
Let's go.
-李斯  DN384...  -对  让他进来
-Reese. DN384...  -Right. Let him in.
我们的监察者有一只爪坏了 所以要减少巡逻
We're cutting short the patrol. Over
收到  扬基17  你可以安全折返
Roger, Yankee-1-7.You are clear to return.
毁灭者...
Terminator!
我梦见一些狗
I was dreaming about dogs.
我们用它们来发现毁灭者
We use 'em to spot Terminators.
你的世界很可怕
Your world is pretty terrifying.
老友  你里面有只死猫吗?
Hey, buddy, you got a dead cat in there or what?
可能的回应: 是  不是或走开
去你的  混蛋
Fuck you, asshole.
妈妈的小屋 大熊镇云杉路181号
该死
God damn.
谢谢
Thank you.
迪基旅馆
这个够不够?
Is this enough?
够了  我不想问你从哪得来的
Yeah, it's enough. I don't wanna ask where you got it.
-来了  -我们要一个房间
-I'm coming.  -We need a room.
-好的  -要有厨房
-Ok.  -With a kitchen.
有没有厨房的?
Do you have one with a kitchen?
我很想洗澡
I am dying for a shower.
还要检查你的绷带
We should check your bandage, too.
稍后吧  我要出去买东西
Later. I'm going out for supplies.
拿着这个
Keep this.
妈  我不能告诉你我在哪  有人叫我别说
No, I can't tell you where I am, Mom. I was told not to say.
我要知道在哪能找到你
I need to know where to reach you.
你叫我躲在小屋里
You tell me to hide out at the cabin
但你却不告诉我怎么回事
and you won't tell me what's going on?
我真是担心死了
I am worried sick here.
好吧  这是电话号码
OK. OK, here's the number.
-准备好了吗  -嗯  说吧
-You ready?  -Yes. Go ahead.
是4085551439...九号房
It's 408 555 1439. Room nine.
-记下了吗?  -记下了
-Got it?  -I've got it.
我要挂了  抱歉我现在不能多说
I gotta go. I'm sorry I can't tell you more right now.
妈  我爱你
I love you, Mom.
我也爱你
I love you, too, sweetheart.
-迪基旅馆  -把地址给我
-Tiki Motel.  -Give me your address there.
买了什么?
What have we got?
樟脑丸...粟米糖浆...阿摩尼亚
Mothballs...corn syrup...ammonia.
晚餐吃什么?
What's for dinner?
-塑料炸弹  -好极了
-Plastique.  -That sounds good.
这是什么?
What is it?
硝酸甘油固定剂  这样会固定一点
It's a nitroglycerin base. It's a bit more stable.
我小时候学会的
I learned to make it when I was a kid.
不要沾到引线上
Make sure there's none on the threads.
这样
Like this.
把盖扭上
Screw the end cap on.
轻轻的
Very gently.
你的童年一定过得很有趣
You must've had a fun childhood.
很好
That's good.
再多做六个  我会开始做信管
All right. Six more like that and I'll get started on the fuses.
他会找到我们  是不是?
He'll find us, won't he?
可能吧
Probably.
这件事永远不会完结  对吗?
It'll never be over, will it?
看看我  我在颤抖
Look at me. I'm shaking.
好一个传奇人物  你一定很失望了
Some legend. You must be pretty disappointed.
不是  我没有失望
No, I'm not.
凯尔  你那个时代的女人
Kyle, the women in your time,
她们是怎样的?
what are they like?
是精锐的战士
Good fighters.
我不是那个意思
That's not what I meant.
有没有意中人?
Was there someone special?
意中人?
Someone...?
女孩子
A girl, you know.
没有
No.
从来没有
Never.
从来没有?
Never?
我很难过  我真的很难过
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
这么多痛苦
So much pain.
痛苦是可以抑制的  只要你不去想它
Pain can be controlled. You just disconnect it.
那么你没有感觉?
So you feel nothing?
约翰·康纳曾经给我一张你的照片
John Connor gave me a picture of you once.
当时我不明白原因
I didn't know why at the time.
它很旧了  有点破烂  也褪色了
It was very old, torn, faded.
你当时很年轻  就像现在一样  看来有点悲伤
You were young like you are now. You seemed just a little sad.
我时常猜想你当时在想什么
I used to always wonder what you were thinking at that moment.
我谨记着每一条线
I memorised every line,
每一条曲线
every curve.
萨拉  我穿越了时空来找你
I came across time for you, Sarah.
我爱你  我一直爱着你
I love you. I always have.
我不该那样说的
I shouldn't have said that.
想快点
Think fast.
交换位置
Trade places.
快点  开快点
Faster. Drive faster.
凯尔  我的天
Kyle. Oh, my God.
混蛋
你别走开
You stay here.
我们快离开
Let's get outta here.
下车
Get out.
凯尔  站起来
Kyle. Come on. Get up.
帮我
Help me.
来吧
Come on.
帮我  快走...
Help me. Get out. Get out.
走
Get out.
快点
Faster.
不要停  走
Don't stop. Run.
萨拉?
Sarah.
凯尔
Kyle.
凯尔  我们成功了  我们成功了
We did it, Kyle. We got him.
不
No.
等一会
Wait.
你干什么?
What are you doing?
掩护  令它追踪不到我们
Cover, so he can't track us.
启动自动序列
快点  来吧
Come on.
不  凯尔  来吧
No. Kyle. Come on.
-来吧  -别理会我
-Come on.  -Leave me here.
快走  李斯  站起来  士兵
Move it, Reese. On your feet, soldier.
站起来  快走
On your feet. Move it.
后面  去后面
Get back. Go back.
-萨拉  快逃  -不
-Run, Sarah.  -No.
快跑
Run.
来吧  混蛋
Come on, mother fucker.
不...
No.
启动卸货
混蛋  你被毁灭了
You're terminated, fucker.
凯尔
Kyle.
第7个录音 11月10日
Tape 7, November 10th.
我说到哪里?
Where was I?
最难决定的是该告诉你什么和不告诉你什么
What's difficult is trying to decide what to tell you and what not to.
我还有时间考虑
But I guess I have a while
在你长大到明白这些录音之前
before you're old enough to understand these tapes
现在来说 这些录音只是给我自己的  好让我理清头绪
They're more for me at this point just so that I can get it straight.
入满它
Fill her up.
我是否该告诉你  关于你父亲的事?
Should I tell you about your father?
孩子 那是个难题
Boy, that's a tough one.
会影响你派他来这的决定吗
Will it effect your decision to send him here
知道他是你父亲
knowing that he is your father?
如果你不派凯尔来  就不会有你
If you don't send Kyle, you can never be.
天  想着这件事会使人发疯的
God, a person could go crazy thinking about this.
我相信我会告诉你的
I suppose I will tell you.
这是我至少该做的
I owe him that.
也许这有帮助的  如果...
Maybe it'll help if...
你知道这个 在我们共处的短暂的时光里
you know that in the few hours that we had together,
我们爱了一生一世
we loved a lifetime's worth.
-他刚刚说什么?  -他说  "小姐  你很漂亮"
-What did he just say?  -He says you're very beautiful.
他不敢问你拿五元的照相费
He is ashamed to ask you for five dollars for this picture.
但如果他不问你要  他父亲就会打他
But if he doesn't, his father will beat him.
孩子  真会做生意
Pretty good hustle, kid.
他刚刚说什么?
What did he just say?
他说 有一场风暴要来了
He said there's a storm coming in.
我知道
I know.
鸣谢赫伦·艾里逊